Chapter 4: Dumbledore

Harry paused just short of the gargoyles outside Dumbledore's office, and turned to Minerva and Filius. "We need the Headmaster's help with the upgraded security for the school in general, but could we not mention the precautions we're planning for me and my friends in particular? Actually, could we present the school-wide security upgrade as something that the three of us worked out together after I said I didn't think the castle was safe enough? That's technically true, and it might save us a lot of trouble."

There was a long pause, and then a reluctant-seeming nod from Minerva. Harry and Minerva both turned to Filius, who still seemed to be arguing with himself, and waited.

Finally, Filius looked up at them. "I'm sorry, Harry. I understand your reasons, but I will not deliberately mislead the Headmaster without far better reason than this."

Harry paused for a moment, and then nodded. "I understand, Professor."

Minerva approached one of the gargoyles and murmured a password, and the three ascended the rotating spiral staircase. The ancient wooden door swung open as they reached it, revealing a worried-looking Albus Dumbledore sitting behind his desk. He beckoned them in, but gave no smile or word of greeting.

Filius broke the silence. "Headmaster, we have some suggestions for improving Hogwarts' security."

Albus Dumbledore smoothed his face and turned his gaze upon Filius Flitwick. When he spoke, his voice was without affect. "I believe I made a mistake today, Filius. I allowed a child to take up an adult's mantle, and to assume more power than any child should wield."

The three of them stared at the old man, completely lost for words. After a few seconds, Minerva took over. "Albus, the safety of our students is my responsibility as well as yours. Mr Potter's new status is a different question entirely - we have a duty to keep our students as safe as we reasonably can, and that duty does not depend on whether Mr Potter is a child or an adult."

Albus smiled, eyes twinkling. "Priorities, Minerva, priorities. This young man shakes the very foundations of Magical Britain, and I must deal with that before I concern myself with schoolboy scuffles."

She stared at him. "Albus, these are children's lives in our hands! If you are unwilling or unable to carry out your obligations as keeper of the wards, then you must delegate that task to myself and Filius! I mean no disrespect, of course, and I understand that you have other responsibilities to consider. But Albus, at least allow us to fulfil these obligations on your behalf."

Albus still looked faintly amused. "As you say, Minerva, I am responsible for the safety of our students. I trust the current security because I personally know how it works. If I were to allow anyone else to tamper with those protections, then I could no longer personally guarantee the safety of Hogwarts. I shall consider your suggestions in due course, but they must wait until I have leisure to do so."

Minerva visibly calmed herself, still staring incredulously at her old friend. "Albus, Mr Malfoy nearly died. As far as we know he would indeed have died, were it not for the protection which Professor Quirrell had laid upon him - protection in addition to the security which you insist is completely reliable. Miss Granger and her friends would have been grievously injured, and possibly even killed outright, were it not for the actions of that same Professor Quirrell. The Defence Professor, Albus. The Defence Professor. How safe is Hogwarts, really?"

Dumbledore sighed. "It all comes back to Harry, doesn't it? His pet gang, his two best friends, and of course his mentor. I'm sorry, Minerva, but it is clear to me that you lack perspective in this matter. For now you must simply trust me, I'm afraid - it will become clearer to you in time."

Filius spoke up, his high-pitched voice perfectly steady. "Do I lack perspective also, Headmaster?"

Albus raised his eyebrows. "I can only judge you on your opinions, Filius. If you agree with Minerva when her judgement is thus clouded by sentiment, then I must conclude that your judgement is similarly clouded."

As Filius goggled in silence, Harry spoke up. "Headmaster, you once sought my advice on a matter of Hogwarts security. I believe that my opinion should therefore carry some weight in your considerations, but I have a more fundamental question for you. What exactly would it take to change your mind on this particular point?"

Dumbledore stared at Harry. "I'm afraid I do not understand the question. Why should I tell you how to change my mind, if indeed such a thing is possible?"

"It's a basic test of rationality, Headmaster - falsifiability. If a belief is founded on appropriate evidence, then you should be able to give at least one example of counter-evidence which would, hypothetically, falsify your belief. The great biologist J.B.S. Haldane, for instance, when asked this exact question in relation to the theory of evolution, cited fossil rabbits in the pre-Cambrian. There are no such things, of course, but if there were then they would in fact be sufficient evidence to falsify the basic theory of evolution. In the same way, you should be able to give some example of evidence which would change your mind. If you can't, then you're effectively conceding that your belief is irrational."

"And what of your conviction that Miss Granger is a good person, Harry? Is that falsifiable?"

"Of course. Prove to me that Hermione has done something morally repugnant, like for instance torturing innocent children, and I'll abandon that belief. Can you tell us some form of evidence which would persuade you that Professor McGonagall is not in fact intellectually crippled by her emotions?"

"I have lived a long time, Harry Potter, and I have learned a great deal. I do not believe that I am capable of explaining this to you in a way that you would find convincing. I do not believe that you are capable of understanding. Perhaps when you are older."

Apparently it was possible to be angry despite the peace of the phoenix. Harry reined in his temper, refusing to be played.

"Headmaster, you declined to allow upgrading of the wards, on the grounds that you would then be unable to personally guarantee the safety of Hogwarts. Can you offer that guarantee in the present circumstances?"

Dumbledore nodded calmly. "Of course I can. Hogwarts is the safest place in the world."

"Headmaster, may I remind you that Draco Malfoy very nearly died last night? That Hermione Granger, an innocent girl, was framed for the attempted murder? Frankly, my Muggle parents' house is safer than Hogwarts."

Albus Dumbledore looked hurt.

"My dear boy, you know not whereof you speak. Your aunt and uncle's house is in fact a good deal safer than you might think, but even those wards cannot compare to the defences of this castle. I know you're upset, Harry, but what happened last night, whatever it was, was a freak occurrence. It could just as easily have happened anywhere."

"Headmaster, calling something a 'freak occurrence' doesn't make it go away. Had our improvements been in place already, last night's events would have proceeded very differently. And today's, for that matter. There are millions of different 'freak occurrences' that might possibly happen, so the probability of at least one of them happening is worth considering. If we care at all about the safety of this castle's residents, we must improve security enough to make at least most of these 'freak occurrences' survivable. Why exactly are you opposing this?"

The old man stood abruptly and strode towards Harry, anger clear in every movement. "You would lecture me on responsibility, Harry? You should know better."

Harry stepped backwards and turned his gaze to Fawkes, sitting quietly on his perch. "Fawkes, can you scream at Dumbledore for me? Or hit him, or something?"

Fawkes shimmered across the room to fly around Dumbledore's head, screaming and batting him with wingtips. Bentham was only a split-second behind, and Albus shrank back before the onslaught of the two phoenixes. The two birds settled on Harry's shoulders as Dumbledore straightened once more. Dumbledore opened his mouth, but Harry spoke first, holding up his hand for silence.

"Professor Dumbledore, your true reason for opposing this is that you think it would somehow make me more powerful, and you're convinced that I'm going Dark because of power. I would like to point out that I now have far more power than what you were afraid of last time you expressed those fears to me. Do you believe that I am already somewhat Dark?"

Albus bowed his head. "Yes. I do believe it, and for my own part in that I am sorrier than you could imagine."

Harry smiled faintly. "If I'm half-Dark and you're trying your best to save me, then why exactly has your phoenix taken my side so thoroughly as to actually reprimand you? How could I possibly be Dark, with a phoenix on either shoulder? I know the wizarding world as a whole refuses to acknowledge phoenixes as evidence of goodness, but you have your own phoenix - you should know what it means."

Albus shook his head sadly. "We've spoken of this before, young man. A phoenix knows only the battle, and cannot fathom how winning the battle might lose the war. The same, evidently, is true of you also. You lack life experience, Harry. You lack wisdom."

"Do Professor McGonagall and Professor Flitwick also lack life experience, Headmaster? Do they also lack wisdom, contrary to the trust which you place in them as Heads of House? You are unmoved by the consensus of myself, two Heads of House, and two phoenixes (including your own). What more do you want, in order to consider the possibility that the great Albus Dumbledore might have made a mistake? Should I fetch a centaur or a seer?"

Dumbledore did wince at that, but his voice remained calm. "If you are trying to hurt my feelings, Harry, then you have succeeded once more."

Minerva spoke, quietly. "Will nothing move you, Albus? Does our counsel truly count for so little now?"

He sighed. "I truly am sorry, Minerva, but you refuse to comprehend the true danger here."

She gazed at him for a moment, and then turned away. The five of them left together in silence - two Heads of House, two phoenixes, and Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres.

Chapter 5: Transfiguration

As the gargoyles settled back into stony immobility, Minerva turned to Harry.

"We shall discuss this further at a later time, Mr Potter. Right now, you and I have a Transfiguration class to attend."

She turned. "Filius, can we count on your assistance?"

The tiny man nodded. "Of course, Minerva."

He turned and walked away.

Harry and Professor McGonagall hurried towards the Transfiguration classroom, Fawkes and Bentham retaining their positions on Harry's shoulders. Professor McGonagall spoke first.

"Will you oppose the Headmaster directly, Mr Potter?"

"That's certainly a possibility now, Professor. I honestly wish I didn't have to, but I may not have a choice. The Headmaster is willing to let the good guys lose a lot more than I can tolerate, and in this instance he doesn't seem to be aware of the dangers to begin with. Heroic responsibility, you understand – children will suffer and die if I don't do something, and it would be my fault."

"I understand. Be careful, Mr Potter, and good luck."

"Thank you, Professor."

They walked the rest of the way in thoughtful silence.

They entered the room to find it deathly silent. Harry quietly dropped into a spare seat at the back of the room, while Professor McGonagall strode to the front. Unnoticed by Harry, Bentham had faded to the translucent shimmer of an alcohol flame. Fawkes retained his accustomed plumage, but was maintaining something like a Notice-Me-Not charm. Neither bird was noticed by any of the students who turned to gawk briefly at Harry before their attention was captured by Professor McGonagall.

"Today, children," began the calm professional voice of the Transfiguration Professor, just as though nothing out of the ordinary had happened, "we shall learn how much effort it takes to sustain a Transfiguration, and why, at your age, you should not even try. The original Form is not gone, only suppressed; and to maintain that suppression - "

"Excuse me," said Padma Patil. Her voice was shaking and she was visibly trembling, but still she asked the question. "Excuse me, Professor, but what happened with Miss Granger?"

Professor McGonagall paused, then seemed to slump very slightly as she turned to face Padma. "Oh, very well. I suppose this is a matter of public record by now, and I quite see why you are concerned. The story is hardly mine to tell, however - Mr Potter, if you would?"

Harry, the peace of the phoenix upon him, stood up calmly and strode to the front of the classroom. A gasp went around the room as the two phoenixes shimmered into view on his shoulders, but Harry ignored it; he merely bowed slightly to Professor McGonagall. "Thank you, Professor - I appreciate the consideration."

He turned to Padma and the rest of the class.

"I shall begin, Miss Patil, by stating once more that Miss Granger is entirely innocent - you no doubt realise this already, but I must repeat it once more for the benefit of the others in this room. Miss Granger committed one morally questionable act, and one only; when she woke up believing that she had probably killed Mr Malfoy, she did not immediately turn herself in. The entire affair was an elaborate frame job, carried out by a skilled adult. Oh, and Mr Malfoy is innocent also; his only morally questionable act was to arrange a midnight duel with Miss Granger. Remember this, all of you."

Harry stood straight, face deadly serious.

"Now, as for what actually happened today. You all deserve to know how the Wizengamot actually works, and what sort of a world we actually live in. You also deserve to know how and why it is now changing."

He glanced around the room at his classmates, all of whom were staring intently at him.

"Lord Malfoy was furious, understandably. He declared a Life Debt, and, less understandably, with a little prompting from Lord Jugson he called for Miss Granger to be sent to Azkaban.

The young faces before Harry now wore near-identical looks of slack-jawed horror.

"The Wizengamot agreed. To be clear: earlier today, the Wizengamot voted to send Hermione Granger to Azkaban."

Many of the students cast questioning looks towards Professor McGonagall, but she merely nodded grimly. Harry continued.

"I declared Lord Malfoy's life debt to me for killing You-Know-Who, and offered it up to keep Miss Granger out of Azkaban. Lord Malfoy accepted, but demanded a hundred thousand Galleons as well."

All the other students gasped at once; wealthy families or not, that was an obscene penalty. Harry went on.

"I tried to accept, but Professor Dumbledore overruled me - apparently he's my guardian. To be clear: the Headmaster of Hogwarts acted to send Hermione Granger to Azkaban. I won't call him a bad person, but you should all understand what he's willing in service of what he believes is right. I warned him that I wouldn't let Hermione Granger go to Azkaban, but he didn't believe me."

Harry paused, and gestured towards Bentham.

"Bentham here came to me as I stood there, and he took me to Azkaban before Hermione could be taken there. I used my Patronus - yes, I do have one, but it's weird - I used my Patronus to destroy every Dementor in Azkaban."

The room was thrown into uproar, which lasted approximately two seconds before Professor McGonagall cast a wide-angle silencing charm. She dispelled it a moment later, but the silence held. Harry continued.

"As I was saying, I destroyed every Dementor in Azkaban before returning to the Hall of the Wizengamot. I then resolved my differences with Lord Malfoy and most of the Wizengamot; Hermione won't be going to Azkaban, and I'm not going into debt to House Malfoy. I also took up my family title - technically I'm Lord Potter now, though I will still answer to 'Harry'."

He grinned cheekily, savouring the looks of bewilderment and disbelief on his classmates' faces.

"And to answer your question more directly, Miss Patil: Miss Granger is currently asleep in the infirmary, suffering nothing worse than emotional exhaustion."

Padma sagged with relief, and Terry Boot spoke up.

"So who is this 'skilled adult' who framed Hermione?"

Harry spread his hands.

"I don't know, Mr Boot. I have my suspicions, but I can't actually prove anything."

Terry looked thoughtful.

"So has Professor Quirrell been arrested yet?"

Harry smiled faintly.

"I believe that Professor Quirrell was in fact being held for questioning, but he's probably been released already. As far as the Ministry is concerned there was no adult perpetrator - only a twelve-year-old girl guilty of attempted murder. And as for your implied accusation of Professor Quirrell for the adult crime which we know to have been committed, I can neither confirm nor deny anything about my private suspicions in relation to any individual."

Kevin Entwhistle spoke. "Is that Dumbledore's phoenix on your other shoulder?"

Harry nodded. "Fawkes, yes."

"Is he your phoenix now? Can that even happen?"

"I suppose it is possible, but no. Fawkes will still go back to Dumbledore."

"And is the other one - Bentham? - your phoenix now? Like, will he stay with you?"

Harry nodded again. "I believe so."

Michael Boot spoke up.

"General, you've deliberately told us bad things about the Headmaster - you even said it was because you wanted us to know. Are you planning to lead students in open defiance of the Headmaster?"

Professor McGonagall flinched at that, although fortunately no one was looking at her. Harry, at whom everyone was now staring, did not flinch. Instead he paused for a moment before casting a faintly apologetic glance at Professor McGonagall, who merely looked resigned. He then turned back to Terry, face now showing something of his anger.

"That, Mr Boot, is an excellent question."

Harry then told the story of his meeting with Professors McGonagall and Flitwick, though he did omit the more personal discussion between himself and Minerva. He told the story of their meeting with the Headmaster, omitting nothing except the details of the specific safety precautions suggested.

"And so you see, Mr Boot, that the Headmaster is so worried about me that he is willing to compromise the safety and security of Hogwarts and its students rather than listen to my suggestions. I do not do this lightly, of course, but I am indeed planning to lead students in at least applying pressure to the Headmaster to change his mind. I do respect the institution of Headmaster, and I do respect Professor Dumbledore himself, but I value your safety – our safety – much more highly than any of that."

Harry looked around at the shocked faces, but there were no more questions. He retook his seat at the back of the room, and Professor McGonagall began her class.

Chapter 11: Reacquaintance

Author's Note: Here's the chapter as promised, but after this it'll be monthly updates. I've discovered that I can't maintain the fortnightly schedule for three stories while working full-time - I think it's affecting the quality of the stories (not to mention the quality of my life), and I'm not willing to do that. Monthly should mean I can write longer and better-polished chapters. Anyway, next chapter after this will be up on July 1.

The moment Harry and Hermione arrived in the Great Hall with Bentham, they were met by Professor Quirrell. Inclining his head slightly, he addressed Hermione.

"Miss Granger, might I have a moment of your boyfriend's time?"

This left Hermione flustered for a number of reasons, not all of them anticipated by Quirrell, but Harry intervened before she could gather her wits enough to say anything at all.

"I'm afraid that's not going to happen, Professor Quirrell. Put simply, right now I'm not letting Hermione out of my sight for any reason. I very nearly lost her today, and I'm finally taking security seriously."

Quirrell raised an eyebrow. "Really, Mr Potter? You believe yourself so much more capable than Miss Granger, that your mere presence within sight of her is both necessary and sufficient for her safety? I fear you are forgetting your lessons."

Harry flinched, he couldn't help that, but he had expected this. He paused for a moment, face carefully neutral as he considered his response.

"I do have weaknesses, Professor - everyone has weaknesses, I haven't forgotten that. I do think Hermione's a lot safer with me than on her own, though, partly because I lack some of her weaknesses and partly because most dangers are a lot less severe for two people working together than for one person working alone. It goes the other way too, don't forget - I know that I've just painted a big target on myself by what I did today, and I think I'm much safer with Hermione than on my own."

"And in that, Mr Potter, you most definitely have not learned the larger lesson. While I intend no disrespect to Miss Granger's school performance, nor even to her performance as a general, she is now unquestionably a liability to you. Your enemies can now hurt you by hurting her."

Harry shoved his temper back down, still keeping his face carefully neutral. This was a crucial contest, and he couldn't afford to lose.

"With respect, sir, that was already the case. I am not now choosing for Hermione's well-being to affect my own - in reality, I'm just finally taking appropriate steps in response to that admitted vulnerability. Honestly sir, after today's Wizengamot session, isn't it painfully obvious to everyone how much Hermione matters to me?"

Ice-blue eyes met furious green.

"That, Mr Potter, is precisely my point. You have acknowledged a weakness, and yet your only response is to raise the stakes without adding more than token safeguards. You are not thinking clearly, Mr Potter, and your sentimental foolishness will inevitably cost you a great deal. When it does, do not say that I did not warn you."

Harry shrugged. "Your argument is not new to me, Professor. I disagree, as you are well aware. Now, what did you want to talk about? Hermione already knows what happened today, so there shouldn't be anything that she shouldn't hear."

Harry noticed a brief flicker in Quirrell's mask in response to that, a fleeting glance towards Hermione. Oops. A moment later, Quirrell turned to address Hermione. His eyes met hers earnestly, but then he flinched involuntarily before he could even start to speak. An awkward silence fell, as all three of them rapidly considered their options. Harry spoke first, outrage perfectly clear in the tone and volume of his voice. This needed to be overheard.

"What the hell do you think you're doing, Professor Quirrell? You just tried to rape my friend's mind! Did you really think you could get away with that? That we wouldn't notice, or that we wouldn't do anything about it?"

Quirrell replied more quietly, though still loudly enough for a few nearby people to hear. "This is not a discussion for the Great Hall, Mr Potter. Shall we move it to my office? I can have food sent."

Harry shook his head furiously. Knowing that almost the entire Hall would be staring at him by now, he quickly summoned Dumbledore and McGonagall with a glance and a gesture. As he turned back to Quirrell, he noted fleetingly (and with considerable relief) that Professor Flitwick was already striding towards him. Taking a deep breath, Harry once more addressed Quirrell and the Hall at large.

"No, Professor Quirrell. This is not a discussion for closed doors and political bargaining. It has to be public."

At this point Professor Flitwick arrived, wand drawn but not aimed. His voice rang out high and clear, with no trace of its usual self-deprecating jollity.

"What's the problem, Mr Potter?"

Harry, wand likewise in hand and voice practically a snarl, answered Flitwick without taking his eyes off Quirrell.

"Professor Quirrell here just attempted Legilimency on Hermione."

The tiny Charms professor showed the sheer shock of it, but even as he flinched he was suddenly pointing his wand at Quirrell. Dumbledore and McGonagall, arriving at this point, followed his example. They both kept their eyes and wands on Quirrell as Dumbledore addressed Harry.

"Harry?"

Harry carefully softened his voice. "He tried to read Hermione's mind, Headmaster."

The Headmaster wasn't particularly shocked by this, of course, knowing that Severus Snape had been doing the same thing to many students for years. On the other hand, he knew how Harry felt about the practice, and he also knew the law. It was a bit early in the year to be losing the Defence Professor already, especially such an extraordinarily competent one, but Harry's obvious fury made the choice a simple one.

"Would you like me to call the Aurors back, Harry?"

Regret was clear on Harry's face, but he nodded without hesitation.

"Yes please, Headmaster."

Quirrell twirled his wand nonchalantly, a mocking smile on his face. "Am I to be arrested again so soon, then, and on the word of a child?"

Dumbledore was busy sending his Patronus to fetch the Aurors, so it was McGonagall who answered.

"Yes, Quirinus. I'm afraid you are. While we cannot prove your involvement in the incident involving Miss Granger and Mr Malfoy, we certainly can do something about your attempt to Legilimise Miss Granger."

He spread his hands. "What evidence have you seen, other than Mr Potter's bare accusation? Is it not more plausible that Mr Potter is merely looking for a villain to explain away his girlfriend's misdeeds, and has settled on me as an easy target? The accusation itself is hardly plausible, in any case - even if I had attempted to access Miss Granger's mind, how exactly could these children have detected and correctly identified the attempt?"

Flitwick stepped forward half a pace, wand still steadily aimed at the centre of Quirrell's chest. "The details can wait until the Aurors arrive, but I vouch for their abilities in this regard."

Quirrell's face became a blank mask of concentration, his body a coiled spring. His wand was now firmly in hand. Flitwick began to drift around to Quirrell's right, and McGonagall to his left. Both looked tense and more than a little nervous, but their wands remained aimed and ready as they moved. Harry quietly slipped behind Dumbledore and backed away a half-dozen paces, pulling Hermione with him. If this became a fight, it would be far above their level - they would be liabilities, plain and simple. He exchanged a glance and a nod with Bentham on his shoulder, but raised his strongest shield regardless - it might buy them a vital split-second, if the situation went badly. Hermione held his hand tightly.

Elsewhere in the Hall, the more intelligent prefects were quietly herding students away from the developing confrontation.

The silence held.

It was to this silence that the Auror trio returned, slipping quietly into the Hall. They took in the situation at a glance; Komodo made a quick gesture as he entered, and Butnaru and Goryanof drifted away either side of him as the three rapidly closed the distance to the looming conflict. Only when they were in position around Quirrell, forming a second ring in the gaps left by the professors, did Komodo finally speak.

"What's the allegation, and what's the evidence?"

The professors glanced at each other, wondering who should speak, but Harry spoke up first.

"Attempted Legilimency on Hermione Granger, right here in the Great Hall. The immediate evidence is my word and Hermione's, but we'll have plenty more for when it goes to trial."

Auror Komodo glanced at Albus Dumbledore. "Do you vouch for this accusation, Chief Warlock?"

Dumbledore nodded, never taking his eyes off Quirrell. "I do, Auror Komodo. I have never yet known Harry Potter to tell a lie, and the mere idea of Hermione Granger doing so is absurd. If they both say that Quirinus Quirrell attempted Legilimency upon Miss Granger, then Quirinus Quirrell attempted Legilimency upon Miss Granger."

Komodo nodded grimly. "Thank you, sir. Quirinus Quirrell, you are under arrest for attempted Legilimency against Hermione Granger. Drop your wand and place your hands on your head."

Quirrell sank smoothly into a crouch, all cold precision and tight-leashed power. Behind him Professor Flitwick exchanged glances with Aurors Butnaru and and Goryanoff, and Butnaru began to count down silently on his fingers.

Suddenly Quirrell exploded into action, a highly choreographed dance performed at lightning speed. He turned fractionally, silently throwing out a rapidly-expanding bludgeoning shield in all directions. In the split-second that this bought him, he leapt towards Minerva McGonagall. An unidentified spell fired behind him sent him flying over her head, and a rapid-fire stream of simple bludgeoners sent her to her knees as he flew overhead. He landed and rolled, flying out of the roll even faster than he had entered it. His wand was now flickering in his hand, scattering a hail of curses around the Hall as he dodged or deflected the few spells that his pursuers managed to fire, and he was running far faster than any human body could manage without magical help. The ancient double doors were shut and locked - Komodo was no fool - but with a twitch of Quirrell's wand they blew away in a cloud of splinters.

The massive front doors, closed but not locked, fared no better a few seconds later. As those once-mighty slabs left the castle as a shock-wave of debris, Quirrell scattered curses into the stonework above the gaping hole they left behind. He crossed the threshold horizontal and still accelerating, clearing it less than a second before the first massive stone smashed down onto the flagstones. Beyond that he was simply gone, obscured and protected from his pursuers by a cascade of collapsing masonry and a choking cloud of dust.